In this and the next
在接下来两节视频中
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
video I want to work
我要通过讲解
through a detailed example, showing
一个具体的例子来解释
how a neural network can compute
神经网络是如何计算
a complex nonlinear function of
关于输入的复杂的非线性函数
the input and hopefully, this will
希望这个例子可以
give you a good sense of why
让你了解为什么
Neural Networks can be used
神经网络可以用来
to learn complex, nonlinear hypotheses.
学习复杂的非线性假设
Consider the following problem where
考虑下面的问题
we have input features x1
我们有二进制的
and x2 that are binary
输入特征
values, so either zero or one.
x1 x2 要么取0 要么取1
So x1 and x2 can each
所以x1和x2只能
take on only one of two possible values.
有两种取值
In this example, I've drawn
在这个例子中 我只画出了
only two positive examples and
两个正样本和
two negative examples, but you
两个负样本
can think of this as a
但你可以认为这是一个
simplified version of a
更复杂的学习问题的
more complex learning problem where
简化版本
we may have a bunch
在这个复杂问题中 我们可能
of positive examples in the upper
在右上角有一堆正样本
right and the lower left and
在左下方有
a bunch of negative examples to notify
一堆用圆圈
the circles, and what
表示的负样本
we'd like to do is learn a nonlinear, you know,
我们想要学习一种非线性的
decision boundary that we
决策边界来
need to separate the positive and the negative examples.
区分正负样本
So how can a neural
那么 神经网络是
network do this and rather than
如何做到的呢？
use an example on the
为了描述方便我不用右边这个例子
right. I'm going to use this, maybe easier
我用左边这个例子
to examine example on the left.
这样更容易说明
Concretely, what this is
具体来讲 这里需要计算的是
is really computing the target
目标函数y
label y equals x1 XOR x2.
等于x1异或x2
Or this is actually the
或者 y也可以等于
x1 XNOR x2 function
x1 异或非 x2
where XNOR is the alternative
其中异或非表示
notation for "not x1 or x2".
x1异或x2后取反
So x1, XOR or
X1异或X2
x2 - that's true only
为真当且仅当
if exactly one of
这两个值
x1 or x2 is equal to 1.
X1或者X2中有且仅有一个为1
It turns out that the specific
如果我
example I'm going to use works out
用XNOR作为例子
a little bit better if we
比用NOT作为例子
use the XNOR example, instead.
结果会好一些
These two are the same, of course.
但这两个其实是相同的
It means not x1 XOR
这就意味着在x1
x2, and so we're going
异或x2后再取反 即
to have positive examples
当它们同时为真
if either both are true or
或者同时为假的时候
both are false and we'll
我们将获得
have that's y equals 1, y equals 1 and
y等于1
we're going to have y equals 0 if
y为0的结果
only one of them is
如果它们中仅有一个
true and we want
为真 y则为0
to figure out if we can
我们想要知道是否能
get a neural network to fit to this sort of training set.
找到一个神经网络模型来拟合这种训练集
In order to build up
为了建立
to a network that fits the
能拟合XNOR运算
XNOR example, we're going
的神经网络 我们先
to start to a slightly simpler one
讲解一个稍微简单
and show a network that fits the AND function.
的神经网络 它拟合了“且运算”
Concretely, lets say we
假设我们
have inputs x1 and
有输入x1和
x2 that are again binary. So, it's either zero or one.
x2 并且都是二进制 即要么为0要么为1
And let's say our target
我们的目标
labels y are you know, is
函数y正如你所知道的
equal to x1 and x2.
等于x1且x2
This is a logical AND.
这是一个逻辑与
So can we get a
那么 我们怎样得到一个
one unit network to compute
具有单个神经元的神经网络来计算
this logical AND function?
这个逻辑与呢
In order to do so, I'm
为了做到这一点
going to actually draw in
我也需要画出偏置单元
the bias unit as well, the plus one unit.
即这个里面有个+1的单元
Now, let me just assign some
现在 让我给这个网络
values to the weights or
分配一些权重
the parameters of this network.
或参数
I am going to write down the parameters on this diagram.
我在图上写出这些参数
Write minus 30 here
这里是-30
plus 20 and plus
正20
20 and what this means
正20 即我给
is that I'm assigning a value
x0前面的
of minus thirty to the
系数赋值
value associated with x0.
为-30.
This is plus 1 going
这个正1会
to this unit and a
作为这个单元的值
parameter value of plus 20
关于20的参数值
that multiplies in x1 in
且x1乘以+20
a value of plus 20 for
以及x2乘以+20
the parameter that multiplies into x2.
都是这个单元的输入
So, concretely, this is saying
所以
that my hypotheses h of
我的假设?(x)
x is equal to
等于
g of  -30 + 20x1 + 20x2.
g(-30 + 20x1 + 20x2)
So sometimes it's just
在图上画出
convenient to draw these
这些参数和
weights and draw these parameters
权重是很方便很直观的
up here, you know, in the diagram of the neural network.
其实 在这幅神经网络图中
And of course this minus 30
这个-30
this is actually theta 1
其实是θ(1)10
of 1,0.
这个是
This is theta 1
θ(1)11
of 1,1 and that's theta
这是
1 of 1,2
θ(1)12
but it's just easier think about
但把它想成
it as, you know, associating these
这些边的
parameters with the edges of the network.
权重会更容易理解
Let's look at what this little single neuron network will compute.
让我们来看看这个小神经元是怎样计算的
Just to remind you, the sigmoid
回忆一下 s型
activation function g of z looks like this.
激励函数g(z)看起来是这样的
It starts from 0, rises
它从0开始 光滑
smoothly, crosses 0.5, and
上升 穿过0.5
then it asymptotes at one.
渐进到1.
And to give you some landmarks,
我们给出一些坐标
if the horizontal axis value
如果横轴值
z is equal to 4.6, then
z等于4.6 则
the sigmoid function is equal to 0.99.
S形函数等于0.99
This is very close
这是非常接近
to 1 and kind of symmetrically
1的 并且由于对称性
if it is negative 4.6, then
如果z为-4.6
the sigmoid function there is
S形函数
equal to 0.01 which is very close to 0.
等于0.01 非常接近0
Let's look at the four possible input
让我们来看看四种可能的输入值
values for x1 and x2
x1和x2的四种可能输入
and look at whether the hypothesis will
看看我们的假设
open in that case.
在各种情况下的输出
If x1 and x2 are both
如果X1和X2均为
equal to 0 - if
0  那么
you look at this, if
你看看这个 如果
x1 and x2 are both equal
x1和x2都等于
to 0 then the hypotheses of point g of -30.
为0 则假设会输出g(-30)
So, it's like very
g(-30)在图的
far to the left of this diagram.
很左边的地方
This will be very close to 0.
非常接近于0
If x1 equals 0 and
如果x1等于0且
x2 equals 1 then this
x2等于1 那么
formula here evaluates to
此公式等于
g, thus the sigmoid function applied
g关于
to -10 and again,
-10取值
that's, you know, to the far left
也在很左边的位置
of this plot and so,
所以
that's again very close to 0.
也是非常接近0
This is also g of -10.
这个也是g(-10)
That is if x1
也就是说 如果x1
is equal to 1 and
等于1并且
x(2)0, this is -30 plus 20, which is -10.
x2等于0 这就是-30加20等于-10
And finally if
最后 如??果
x1 equals 1, x2 equals
x1等于1 x2等于
1, then you have g of
1 那么这等于
-30 +20 +20,
-30 +20 +20
so that's g of
所以这是
+10, which is
取+10时
therefore very close to 1.
非常接近1
And if you look
如果你看看
in this column, this is
在这一列 这就是
exactly the logical "and" function.
逻辑“与”的计算结果
So, this is computing h of
所以 这里得到的h
x is, you know,
h关于x取值
approximately x1 and x2.
近似等于x1和x2的与运算的值
In other words, it outputs
换句话说 假设输出
1 if and only
1 当且仅当
if x1 and x2 are
x1 x2
both equal to 1.
都等于1
So by writing out our little
所以 通过写出
truth table like this,
这张真值表
we manage to figure out what's
我们就弄清楚了
the logical function that our
神经网络
neural network computes.
计算出的逻辑函数
This network shown here computes
这里的神经网络
the OR function just to
实现了或函数的功能
show you how I worked that out.
接下来我告诉你是怎么看出来的
If you are to write out
如果你把
the hypotheses you find that
假设写出来
it's computing g of
会发现它等于
-10 +20 x1
g关于-10 +20x1
+20 x2. And so
+20x2的取值
if you fill in these values you
如果把这些值都填上
find that's g of
会发现
-10 which is approximately 0,
这是g(-10) 约等于0
g of 10 which is
这是g(10)
approximately 1, and so on.
约等于1
These are approximately 1, and approximately
这个也约等于1
1, and these numbers is
这些数字
essentially the logical OR
本质上就是逻辑或
function.  So, hopefully
运算得到的值 所以 我希望
with this, you now understand how
通过这个例子 你现在明白了
single neurons in a
神经网络里单个的
neural network can be used
神经元在计算
to compute logical functions like AND and OR and so on.
如AND和OR逻辑运算时是怎样发挥作用的
In the next video, we'll continue
在接下来的视频中 我们将继续
building on these examples and work through a more complex example.
讲解一个更复杂的例子
We'll get to show you how
我们将告诉你
a neural network, now with
一个多层的神经网络
multiple layers of units can
怎样被用于
be used to compute more complex
计算更复杂的函数
functions like the XOR function or the XNOR function.
如 XOR 函数或 XNOR 函数